# Joomart Achekeev

joomart.achekeev@gmail.com | (609) 455-3245 | Plainsboro, New Jersey | linkedin.com/in/joomart-achekeev/ | github.com/jomadata | jomadata.github.io

### **Skills**

Data mining, Data Cleaning, Data Processing, Data Engineering, Python, General programming, Functional programming, Object oriented programming, Pandas, NumPy, Scikit-learn, Matplotlib, Seaborn, NLTK, Tensorflow/Keras, Django Templates, Django Rest API, PostgreSQL, Docker, Linux, MS Excel, MS Power Point, Prezi, MS Office, Tableau, others

#### **Profile**

Inquisitive and result-oriented Data Analyst/Data Scientist, with 5+ years of experience in backend web development and an international certification in project management. My approach is based on breaking down the problem into small, easily solvable, parts and tackling them one by one. I seek to continuously develop my skills, expand my knowledge and embrace the world as my data.

# Experience

#### Data Analyst, Oct 2022 - Now

## Lingraphica, United States

- · Pulled data from various databases for further analysis using SQL and pandas framework
- Processed, combined, cleaned and engineered data in Excel and pandas framework
- Analyzed and interpreted data using Tableau, Excel, pandas, matplotlib, and seaborn frameworks
- · Built dashboards, graphs and tables for reporting in Tableau and Excel
- Wrote python code to automate data pulling, combination, processing, cleaning, and engineering to automate reporting

### Online Data Science Immersive Fellow, Oct 2021 – Jan 2022

#### **General Assembly, United States**

Completed 3 individual and 2 team projects with the use of various machine learning models: <u>Linear regression model</u>, <u>Web scraped data and tuned NLP classification model</u>, <u>Decision Tree models</u> (AdaBoostClassifier, DecisionTreeClassifier, ExtraTreesClassifier), <u>Stacked linear regression and neural network model</u>. NLP extraction of additional review dimensions

### Backend web developer, Sep 2017 – Jul 2021

#### Yorc

- Developed backend support for web applications including design and configuration of databases
- Close cooperation with clients on meeting their needs/demands
- Collaboration with UX/UI, Frontend teams to ensure proper frontend-backend integration
- Troubleshooting and reviewing of own, legacy, and colleagues' projects
- Used tech stack: Python 3, Django Rest API, PostgreSQL, Docker, Pandas, Numpy
- Projects developed for banks, trade companies, and international organizations (USAID, DPI)

### Junior Backend web developer, Aug 2016 – Aug 2017

#### **Put In Byte**

- Design and configuration of databases and backend applications
- Developed, tested, and debugged programs for internal and client use
- Trained in reviewing Python code for troubleshooting and debugging
- Unit testing of own and colleagues' codes
- Used tech stack: Python 3, Django Templates, PostgreSQL, Docker
- · Projects developed for travel agencies, media companies, and international organizations (UNICEF)

## **Backend web development intern,** Apr 2016 – Jul 2016

## Put In Byte

- Designed robust, scalable, secure, and globalized web-based applications to ensure the continuity of all business processes and client satisfaction.
- Backend framework design in Django Templates, Django Rest API basics
- · Collaboration with frontend developers to ensure proper frontend-backend integration
- Multiprocessing web scrapper development (BeautifulSoup)

#### Research Project Manager, Nov 2013 – Mar 2016

## M-Vector Research and Consulting

- Managing several analytical research projects (social and marketing) at a time
- Cooperation with field data gathering team
- · Full research project management from initial problem identification to final research reporting (narrative, analytical and financial)

Review and submission of the final version of the research report

# Research Analyst, Feb 2011 – Oct 2013

# M-Vector Research and Consulting

- Development of data collection methods and instruments
- Data processing, analysis, and cleaning
- Overview of other available research papers in the field or on a similar topic
- Develop narrative, analytical and financial reports
- Develop visual report components (graphs, general tables)

### **Education**

# **General Assembly**

Data Science Immersive Graduate (Certification)

### **OSCE Academy**

Master of Arts of Economics (Diploma in Economic Governance and Development)

# **American University in Central Asia**

Bachelor of Business Administration (Diploma in Marketing and Management)

### Certification

Project Management Level-C Certificate from International Project Management Association (#LATV-C0155) - Dec 2020